Willison, Malcolm; Papers apap055
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Economic and Social Action, 1958-1997; 6; 3.2 cubic ft.
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Finance Committee -- Fund Raising, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 13)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Gardenway Community Gardens Project, 1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 14)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Hard-to-House Training Project, 1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 15)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Memorandums of Understanding and Agreement, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 16)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), National Campaign for Human Development, 1984-1986 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 17)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT)Neighborhood News, 1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 18)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), New York State Funding Initiatives, 1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 19)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Private Funding, 1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 20)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Private Funding, Hellman Family Foundation, 1983-1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 21)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Troy Rehabilitation and Improvement Program, Inc., 1985 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 22)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), Work Logs, 1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 23)
  - New Citizen, 1977 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 24)
  - New Jobs for a New Schenectady, 1993 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 25)
  - New Start Project, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 26)
  - New Start Project, Grant Information, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 27)
  - New Start Project, Work Logs, 1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 28)
  - New York State Coalition for Criminal Justice, 1980-1982 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 29)
  - New York State Coalition for Criminal Justice, Good Time Reform Project, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 30)
  - New York State Council of Churches, 1993 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 31)
  - New York State Environmental Congress, 1992 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 32)
  - Nonviolence Initiatives, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 33)
  - Nuclear Freeze Campaign, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 34)
  - Nuclear Freeze Campaign, The Freeze Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 35)
  - Peace Initiatives, 1974-1996 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 36)
  - Peace Initiatives, Beyond War Project, 1984 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 37)
  - Peace Initiatives, The Draft, 1983 (Box 2 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 38)
  - Peace Initiatives, Military Spending, 1979-1982 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 1)
  - Peace Initiatives, Nuclear Disarmament, 1974-1983 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 2)
  - Peace Initiatives, Nuclear Disarmament, 1982-1996 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 3)
  - Peace Initiatives, Peace Action, 1995-1997 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 4)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, 1983 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 5)
  - Politics, 1978-1984 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 6)
  - The Politics of Food, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 7)
  - Poverty, 1958-1991 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 8)
  - Public Utilities and the Energy Crisis, 1975-1978 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 9)
  - Report, "Arms and the Art of Compromise", 1983 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 10)
  - Report, "Building a Progressive Vision and Program for New York's Capital Region and Beyond, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 11)
  - Report, "Bureaucratic Insurgency: The Vatican and the Crisis of Modernization", Undated (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 12)
  - Report, "Business Blues: Pataki tax and Economic Plan Creates inequalities and Hurts Job Growth", 1996 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 13)
  - Report, "Cambridge and Nuclear Weapons", Undated (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 14)
  - Report, "Growing Together within the Capital Region", 1996 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 15)
  - Report, "How Would the US Survive a Nuclear War?", 1982 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 16)
  - Report, "Jobs and the Environment", 1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 17)
  - Report The Militant's Guide: Democratic Workers Party, 1979 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 18)
  - Report, "MX Missile Basing", 1981 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 19)
  - Report, "Pittsfield and Nuclear War", Undated (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 20)
  - Saratoga Peace Alliance (SPA), 1982-1983 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 21)
  - Saratoga Peace Alliance Newsletter (SPAN), 1982-1984 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 22)
  - Schenectady 2000, 1992-1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 23)
  - Schenectady 2000, Upper Erie Boulevard Task Force, 1993-1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 24)
  - Schenectady Alliance for Reproductive Freedom, 1979 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 25)
  - Schenectady Community Action Program, Community Needs Assessment, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 26)
  - Schenectady County Public Library, Small Business Focus Group, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 27)
  - Schenectady Economic Initiative, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 28)
  - Schenectady MLK, Jr. Coalition, 1993-1994 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 29)
  - Seneca Army Depot, 1983 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 30)
  - SENSES, 1992-1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 31)
  - SENSES, Community Economic Development, Undated (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 32)
  - Sex and Ethics, 1976-1979 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 33)
  - Siena College, 1984 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 34)
  - Social Justice Center, 1982-1983; 1996 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 35)
  - Solidarity Committee, 1992-1995 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 36)
  - Study Circle Consortium, 1983-1994; 1996 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 37)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Homelessness and Affordable Housing, 1990 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 38)
  - Study Circle Consortium, New Sweden '88 Seminar, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 39)
  - Study Circle Consortium, New Sweden '88 Seminar, Swedish National Board of Education, 1988 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 1)
  - Tax the Rich, 1992 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 2)
  - Union College, 1992 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 3)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1982 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 4)
  - University Task Force for International Labor, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 5)
  - Upper Hudson Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, 1982-1985; 1993 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 6)
  - Upper Hudson Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, Newsletter, 1983-1984 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 7)
  - Upstate New York Nuclear Freeze News, 1982-1984 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 8)
  - Vietnam, 1965-1967 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 9)
  - Vietnam, Stratton vs. Willison Debate, 1967 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 10)
  - Watergate, 1973 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 11)
  - World Federalist Association, 1984-1996 (Box 4 (6-Economic and Social Action), Folder 12)
- Employee Ownership Project (EOP), 1982-1996; 7; 2 cubic ft.
  Series 7 contains some of the records of the Employee Ownership Project (EOP) from 1982-1996. The records include board meeting agendas and minutes from 1987 to 1996 and committee notes. The budget and finances from 1990-1996 are also included. The Roman Catholic Diocese of Albany funded EOP and some of the records in the series discuss the non-profit, tax-exempt status of the organization along with its structure. EOP took on initiatives such as Employee Stock Ownership Programs and cooperatives. In this capacity, EOP worked closely with the Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), whose records are also included in the series.
  - Able Asbestos Feasibility Study, 1996 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 1)
  - About EOP, 1988-1992 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 2)
  - Adult Learning, Work and Citizenship, 1988 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 3)
  - The Benchmark, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 4)
  - Board Expansion, 1985-1988 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 5)
  - Board Meetings, Agendas and Minutes, 1987-1989 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 6)
  - Board Meetings, Agendas and Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 7)
  - Board Meetings, Agendas and Minutes, 1993-1996 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 8)
  - Board Meetings, Committee of the Whole, 1989-1990 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 9)
  - Budget and Finances, 1990-1996 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 10)
  - Burlington Local Ownership Development Project, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 11)
  - Business Maintenance Organization, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 12)
  - By-laws, 1988 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 13)
  - Campaign for Human Development (CHD), Center for Cooperative Enterprise, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 14)
  - Campaign for Human Development (CHD), Diocesan Development Project, 1990 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 15)
  - CEFAM, Undated (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 16)
  - Changing Work, 1984; 1989 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 17)
  - "The Church and Public Policy", 1986 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1979; 1989-1995 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 19)
  - Community Development Block Grant, 1994; Undated (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 20)
  - Community Loan Fund, 1988-1993 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 22)
  - Democratic Employee Ownership, First Annual Conference and Training, 1989 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 23)
  - Economic Development, 1986-1996 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 24)
  - Economic Development, Senate-Assembly Bill, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 25)
  - Economic Justice for All, 1987 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 1)
  - Employee Ownership, Literature about the Concept, 1982; 1987-1991 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 2)
  - Flyers, 1988-1995 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 3)
  - Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), 1987-1991 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 4)
  - ICA Bulletin, 1987-1996 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 5)
  - Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), Employee Stock Ownership Plans (ESOP), 1990 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 6)
  - Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), ESOP Study Circle, 1983-1990 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 7)
  - Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), Revolving Loan Fund, Undated (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 8)
  - Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA), The Working Knowledge Program, 1987-1990 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 9)
  - Industrial Cooperation Council, Undated (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 10)
  - Labor Area Summary, 1983-1990 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 11)
  - Labor Area Summary, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 12)
  - Labor Area Summary, Annual Report, 1986 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 13)
  - Land Trusts, 1991 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 14)
  - Local Development Corporation, 1987 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 15)
  - Long Term Planning, 1992 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1995 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 17)
  - Neighborhood Action Council of Troy (N-ACT), 1984-1986 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 18)
  - New York Center for Employee Ownership and Participation, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 19)
  - The New American Experiment, 1985 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 20)
  - Personnel Policies, 1987; 1994-1995 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 21)
  - Port of Albany: Economic Impact Study, 1980 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 22)
  - Project Descriptions and Information, 1986-1996 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 23)
  - Report, Building a Cooperative Economy: Lessons from the Black Experience, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 24)
  - Report, Employee Involvement Plans, 1992 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 25)
  - Report, End of an Era, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 26)
  - Report, Managing without Managers, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 27)
  - Report, Worker Education in Sweden, 1988 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 28)
  - Report, Workers' Involvement among Small Manufacturers: The CEO Barrier, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 29)
  - Report, Working for a Living, 1980 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 30)
  - Research, 1984-1987 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 31)
  - Staff Evaluations, 1995-1996 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 32)
  - Strategic and Programmatic Planning, 1988 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 33)
  - Strategic Long Range Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 34)
  - Study Circle Consortium, New Sweden, 1988 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 35)
  - Study Circles, 1982 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 36)
  - Training Conferences, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 37)
  - Unions, Undated (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 38)
  - US-USSR Bridges to Peace, 1989-1991 (Box 2 (7-Employee Ownership Project (EOP)), Folder 39)
- Personal Papers, 1968-1975; 8; 0.2 cubic ft.
  This small series includes information about the Willison home and correspondence.
  - Home, 1968-1975 (Box 1 (8-Personal Papers), Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1981-1996 (Box 1 (8-Personal Papers), Folder 2)